KARLY STARK

EDUCATOR
EXPERIMENTAL FILMMAKER
DIGITIZATION SPECIALIST
CURATOR

PROFILE SUMMARY

My diverse experiences as an educator, experimental filmmaker, media digitization specialist, and curator illustrate an immense passion for image and sound-based medias, and making these medias accessible to larger audiences. My interests lie in: essay filmmaking, media accessibility practices, queer + trans film, public projections, and youth media education.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Digital Photography + Cinematography (Canon, Sony)
- Small Gauge Cinematography (Super 8mm, 16mm)
- Digitization/Preservation Processes, Video & Audio
- Video Projection (Digital, 16mm)
- Editing: Adobe Suite + Final Cut Pro
- Animation and Motion Graphics (AE)
- Media Accessibility Practices
- Youth + Young Adult Media Education
- Program Management + Event Assistance
- · Copywriting, Grant-Writing
- Mutual Aid Organizing

CONTACT

346 45th St. Oakland, CA 94609

Phone: (562) 544-0190

Email: karlystark@gmail.com Website: www.karlystark.com

Pronouns: THEY/THEM

EDUCATION

San Francisco State University 2013-2016

MFA in Cinema

Graduate Hood, College of Liberal & Creative Arts

Thesis: 2076 (Elegy)

Committee: Professor Cheryl Dunye (Chair) +

Professor Greta Snider

University of California, Berkeley 2008-2012

Bachelor of Arts, Film Studies

High Honors, Department of Film & Media Studies

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

EPACENTER, Multimedia Instructor **2023**

Spring 2023. Middle School Photography

Spring 2023. Middle School Filmmaking

Spring 2023. High School Photography (KIPP Esperanza)

Spring 2023. Multimedia Internship (17-18 years)

San Francisco State University, Lecturer 2016-2020

Fall 2020. Cine 303 GWAR: Writing on Cinema - The Monstrous-Feminine

Spring 2020. Cine 630 Workshop in Experimental Documentary: The Essay Film

Spring 2020. Cine 540 Queer & Trans Film Theory

Fall 2019. Cine 325 Focus on Film Topics: The Monstrous-Feminine

Fall 2019. Cine 344 Film Genre: Feminist Science Fiction

Fall 2019. Cine 335 The Art of Cinematography

Fall 2019. Cine 211 Film History 1: 1895-1945

Spring 2019. Cine 540 Queer & Trans Film Theory

Spring 2018. Cine 529 Experimental Filmmaking

Spring 2018. Cine 304 GWAR: Short Animations

Fall 2017. Cine 304 GWAR: Short Animations

Fall 2017 Cine 304 GWAR: Feminist Science Fiction

Spring 2017. Cine 529 Experimental Filmmaking

Fall 2016- Cine 304 Gender and Film

University of California, Berkeley, Reader 2017-2018

Su 2018. Film Genre: History of Animation, Prof. Russell Merritt Spring 2017. Film Genre: History of Animation, Prof. Russell Merritt

Galileo SummerQuest, Lead Instructor 2014-2016

Summer 2014-2016. Lead Instructor (Middle School) - Digital Filmmaking & Photography

SF State University, Graduate Lecturer 2015-2016

Spring 2016. Cine 303 GWAR: Women, Space, and Place Fall 2015. Cine 425 The Art of Cinematography

CURATORIAL + ORGANIZING

2019 | Marin County Film Festival, Juror 2016-2017 | The Great Wall of Oakland, Program Director

2014-2016 | The Great Wall of Oakland, Curator 2016 | "Queer Student Shorts," Frameline SF International LGBT Film Festival, Curator 2015 | "Quoting Ourselves: A Queer Archive," Cesar Chavez Art Gallery, Curator 2014 | Marin County Film Festival, Screener 2012 Bay Area Student Film Festival, Pacific Film Archive, Curatorial Intern

Operations Workleader

UC Berkeley, Media Resources Center (2016-2017, 2012-2013)

Served as workleader of general operations for the center. Supervised and managed 8 student employees, performed circulation support, processed incoming materials for circulation, began the preservation/digitization initiative project, and catalogued entries into our new streaming platform.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Digitization Specialist

UC Berkeley, Library Imaging Services & Media Resources Center (2020-2022)

Worked collaboratively on projects across two teams, creating accessible copies of printed course reserves and rare materials, as well as sound and visual medias. Performed highly technical processes, trained shared staff, analyzed and improved triage workflows, performed complex file management across teams, held office hours for film & media production consultations, and produced/edited animated instructional videos for the Center for Connected Learning.

Digitization Assistant

UC Berkeley, Media Resources Center (2017-2020)

Provided key support in the initiative to digitize and preserve the MRC's vast and celebrated collection of media materials. Created and implemented new workflows, produced preservation copies of materials, trained student employees, and performed file and server management duties.

Program Director

The Great Wall of Oakland (2016-2017)

Supported all programs associated with the Great Wall of Oakland, including First Friday screenings and off-the-wall commissions. Support encompassed curation, coordination and partnership with collaborators and commissioned artists, development and grant-writing, social media, and production/projectionist duties.

FILMOGRAPHY

2018 | Proximity

2016 | 2076 (Elegy)

Distributed by: Canadian Filmmakers Distribution Centre (Toronto, ON) + Collectif Jeune Cinéma (Paris, FR)

2016 | Genetic Memory

2015 | The Problem Is...

2014 | I Am Delighted By Your Alchemy
Distributed by: Collectif Jeune Cinéma (Paris, FR)

Screenings include: BFI Flare London LGBT Film Festival, McEvoy Foundation for the Arts, Crossroads Film Festival, Pacific Film Archive, Artists Television Access, MixNYC Queer Experimental Film Festival, among others.

AWARDS, FELLOWSHIPS, CERTIFICATES

2018 | Berkeley Spot Award, Film Clip Library Project

2017 | YBCA Creative Dissent Fellow, Escuela de Arté Útil w/ Tania Bruguera

2017 | Emerging Queer Scholarship Recipient, Film for Artists Residency: Site & Cycle, Artscape Gibraltar Point, Toronto (cancelled due to flooding) 2016 | Graduate Hood, College of Liberal & Creative Arts. SFSU

2016 | Queer Community All Star Award, SFSU Lavendar Graduation

2015 | Cinefemme Grant Recipient